

+358-50480-2095 ASUC, Maarintie 6, Espoo, Finland alfpooh@gmail.com alf@justbrow.se

I am an entrepreneur, founder of Forethink, experience designer. Building innovative internet advertisement service.

. As a service designer and researcher, I have built my career as user experience expert in global companies such as Microsoft, Nokia, Philips design, Motorola, and LG Electronics for 20 years. Especially, I have strong competence in creating innovative user experience concepts & prototypes, data visualization UX, building elegant user interface, and orchestrating creative design team.

Academic design research is the other pillar of my design career. I hold a doctorate degree in advanced design study. The topic of my research field is focused on Product Service System design for a society. My doctoral thesis was about a service design for public transportation system.

However, for users, I am always a humble listener and curious observer who is trying to understand their deeper needs, and real wants. I truly believe my team can make a great design by understanding users and market.

Personally, I love cooking (Korean+Nordic) for my friends and family.

Work Experience

Forethink, Founder

Feb. 2016 - Sept. 2017

- . Startup for innovating internet advertising ecommerce
- . Building iOS apps (Swift) series Fiksu
- . Leading design and develop an internet advertisement service solution: Vaikutin

Microsoft, Phones, Design

Apr. 2014 - Oct. 2015

- Senior designer, Espoo, Finland
- . Senior user experience designer for mobile phone accessory in Phone UX design
- . Developing an IOT hub application, "Microsoft Gadgets" UI, in a LEAN UX method.
- . Developing the Bluetooth LE IOT Sensor, "Microsoft Treasure Tag" device UI and app. UI
- . Developing Screen Sharing, Miracast mirroring device: Device UX design
- . Developing mobile accessory concept design: Ideation, UX scenario, planning for 2016
- . Developing a stereo BT headset, Van Halen: Device UX design

As IOT (Internet of things) UX expert. Lead UX design from front-end (prototyping, UX workshop) to the end (UI flows, User stories, use cases, UX specs, and fit & finish). # My products in the market

Microsoft Screen Sharing for Lumia Phones Microsoft Treasure Tag

NOKIA

Apr. 2011 – Apr. 2014

• Senior user experience designer, Espoo, Finland

Jan. 2013 -Apr. 2014

- . Windows Mobile Phone application design, IOT Sensor related
- . Developing an activity tracking app. Motion monitor for user's health, wellbeing, UX design
- . Developing the Joyn RCS mobile messenger app. UX design
- Principal user experience designer, Ulm, Germany

June 2012 - Dec. 2012

. For the Meego based platform, developing advanced concept designs

Design innovation in a small screen UX such as QWERTY keypad for smallest smart phone, and natural behaviours with backside touch.

• Principal innovation expert, Beijing, China

April. 2011 – June 2012

- . Product innovation, Feature Phone division
- . Developing prototypes, innovative demonstrators for future Nokia products as chief designer

Lead innovation experts in the UX innovation of Nokia S30/S40 platform. Low cost smart phone UX for B2B; solving daily productivity problems.

INNOUX, Korea Jun. 2010 – Jan.2011

Principal Director

- . A founder and leader of user experience design consulting team
- . A family company of InnoDesign, a total design brand design studio since 1986
- . Chief designer director, project manager, consulting project for KT app store, web design for Korea Telecom (2nd largest mobile carrier in Korea)

My second start-up. UX team building and consulting for clients. Hoped to be a leading front-end UX consultancy for corporates.

Philips Design Consulting, Hong Kong branch

Aug. 2008 - Jul. 2009

Consultant, Interactive Designer

- . Managing and creating interaction design proposal, user interface guide and UI flow.
- . Touch UI for Google Android based mobile multimedia player, "GoGear Connect"
- . Touch & touch-frame UI for digital photo frame
- . Touch based Human-Machine Interface for In Car Entertainment system, CED750, CID2680
- . Implementing Philips Brand Identity Design Architecture

Motorola, Korea Apr. 2001 – Jul.2008

• Senior Design Researcher Human Factors & Design Research Team

Feb. 2006 - July 2008

- . Planning, executing, analyzing, and promoting global design research projects
- . Managing the Perceived Quality audit management
- . Leader of research projects for touch interface principle study
- . Researching and designing a language predictive input system for Asian languages.

Lead Designer

User Interface Design Team

Apr. 2004 - Feb. 2006

- . Managing UI/GUI design team for Sprint US
- . Producing user interface design guidelines and UI flow schematics
- . Designing innovative UI experience for advanced concepts and portfolio products

Design Strategy Planner Global Design Planning Team

Apr. 2001 - Apr. 2004

- . Managing the Global Trend Monitoring Program and published monthly newsletters
- . Researching ethnography researches and trend researches
- . Developing a user experience design strategy, concept and process
- . Developing advanced product design concepts for the future Motorola business

LG Electronics Dec. 1995 – Mar.1998

Industrial Designer
 Research & Simulation design team, Corporate Design Center

- . Designing advanced digital products: design research, concept, and design
- PDA, DVD, Network Computer, Ergonomics keyboard.

	Education
Doctor in Design, advanced design study, Hongik Univ. IDAS, Korea # Research focus on Product-Service System design strategy	2008 –2015
MFA, Industrial Design, Hongik Univ. Korea # Research focus on interaction design and user centered design development	1998 - 2000
BFA, Industrial Design, Hongik Univ. Korea # Focus on product design and advanced concept design	1990 - 1996

Other skills and experience

Patent

• "Content Browsing System with Multi-level Circular Index and Automated Contents Analysis Function"

2005

- . Registered in Korea: KR0363619, USA: US 6,920,445 B2
- . Method and an apparatus for easy contents browsing
- . Sold to a patent holding company. Currently, holding "Inventor's license" for the patent.

Teaching experience (recent)

. 'Human Factors', Hongik university Industrial Design Dept. 2010

- . 'Universal design', Hongik university Industrial Design Dept. 2008
- . 'Design Strategy', The university of Seoul Graduate school 2007

Creative design course development

- . **The** Informance workshop course for designers (advanced design scenario method) since 2010
- . Lego Serious Playtm Creative Workshop course for designers (advanced brainstorming and scenario building) since 2008

IT Skills

#Adobe_suits #Arduino #Swift3 #HTML/CSS #Javascript #GoAnimate #miniTab #MSoffice #Visualstudio #Node.js #Bootstrap

Design Skills

#wireframes #prototyping (Justintime) #storyboards #user-scenario (GoAnimate, Lego Seriousplay) #LeanCanvas #UX flows (user flow, user journey) #Statistics (miniTab) #Graphic-UI (Adobe, Sketch3) #Technical-Drawing (AutoCad)

Certification

- . Leading Service Business Program, Aalto Executive Education, Helsinki, 2015
- . Certificated facilitator for Lego Serious Playtm workshop, Munich, 2012

Portfolio & Work samples

- Linkedin Profile https://fi.linkedin.com/in/alfbae
- Portfolio: https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B5myESs5gGVJWDJ2OElrLS1iTUk/view?usp=sharing
- Work samples:

Number Space Visualization https://drive.google.com/file/d/0BwwPqpnlsIViLU9NU25uVmFSbTQ/view?usp=sharing

Motion monitor project story https://drive.google.com/file/d/0BwwPqpnlsIVidm9VSzZ4aHo3NGc/view?usp=sharing

Motion monitor explainer video https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6bbMzBqZ508

• Doctoral thesis: Product Service System Design for a Flight Luggage Weight Management https://drive.google.com/file/d/0BwwPqpnlsIViVkF4T0dTNGJQSTA/view?usp=sharing

Thanks. This CV is prepared at September. 2017. Alf Bae.